

Ahmad Alaei Chief Operating Officer

No. 101, Besat 2 St., Rouhani Bldv., Mollasadra Ave., Karaj, Iran +98-912-317-5128

alaei.ahmad@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/ahmad-alaei/

Summary

Experienced Chief Operating Officer with a demonstrated history of working in industrial manufacturing projects especially sheet metal products and related processes

Skilled in Operations Management, Strategic Management & Business Planning, Leadership, Teamwork Operations as a member or leader, Project Management (Planning & Controlling), Sales & Logistics Management

Excellent in MS Office
Have a good knowledge of MS Project & Primavera
Familiar with CRM, ERP and Automation or organizational softwares

Fluent in English

Driving license of Iran for more than 15 years without any accident (and less than two fines per year)

Experience

Chief Operating Officer [Shareholder]

Jan 2018 – Present

QM Group (www.qmgroup.ir)

- Shaping the company's overall business strategy
- Identifying SWOT
- Ensuring the business operates within the company's mission statement
- Ensuring financial targets and other agreed targets are met
- Driving the business to increase profits (Responsible for driving the company to achieve and surpass sales, profitability, cash flow and business goals and objectives)
- Providing day-to-day leadership and management and overseeing daily operations and making adjustments as necessary
- Dedication to building and growing a strong and stable workforce
- High-level understanding of all business functions such as IT, HR, Finance, Marketing,
 etc
- Decision-making and problem-solving in pressure situations
- Measuring effectiveness and efficiency of operational processes both internally and externally and finds ways to improve processes

- Developing and implementing growth strategies
- Acting as a liaison between company and client for quality assurance
- Motivating staff to meet or surpass organizational and sales goals
- Providing a system for employee salaries and benefits, and makes sure employees feel valued
- Promoting communication between colleagues for the benefit of information flow and to curb any problems that arise

Operations & Project Manager [Shareholder] Dec 2012 – Dec 2017 QM Group (www.qmgroup.ir)

- Ensuring the business operates within the company's mission statement
- Working with department heads and senior management to get the best performance from staff
- Investigating customer satisfaction and reporting any issues
- Making sure safety regulations are followed
- Planning and monitoring the projects
- Managing the production of the required deliverables
- Planning or implementing material flow management system to meet manufacturing and production requirements
- Managing project risks
- Negotiating with suppliers and finding best price and quality
- Reviewing working practices to ascertain if it is successful and if not, devise an alternative
- Liaising with program managers on customer side
- Monitoring overall progress and use of resources, initiating corrective action where necessary
- Maintaining an awareness of potential interdependencies with other projects and their impact
- Keeping employees motivated and organizing appropriate training
- Working with legal departments on any matters that occur
- Maintaining tools, devices and equipment

Also have a good knowledge and understanding of these issues in manufacturing sheet metal products:

- Prototyping and mass production and their related price/cost ratio
- Price analysis and project estimating in sheet metal products
- Using Kaizen (Plan-Do-Check-Act) continues improvement method in daily procedures and mass production
- Working times, performance of operators and operation cycles of NC press break, hydraulic and mechanical benders, guillotine, grinding machines, drilling machines, hydraulic and mechanical pressing machines, MIG and TIG welding, press welding machine, drilling, brushing and finishing tools
- Different sheet metal sizes, thicknesses and material
- Minimizing wastage of raw material

Sales & Logistics Manager [Shareholder]

Sep 2007 – Oct 2012

Eris (www.eris.ir)

- Explaining technical security solutions to customers, understanding their requirements and providing basic site surveys, system designs and quotations
- Organizing the storage and distribution of goods and balancing them between projects and agencies in order to maintain the contract conditions and reach the highest profit
- Analyzing the financial impact of proposed logistics changes, such as routing, shipping modes, product volumes or mixes, or carriers
- Implementing specific customer requirements, such as internal reporting or customized transportation or installation metrics
- Planning material flow management systems to meet project or contract requirements to prevent installation or delivery lag
- Supervising the installation team to go through the schedule and meet the customer requirement
- Finalizing the contracts or projects, coordinating other departments to ensure reaching the targets and receiving approvals and checking financial issues solved in the best manner

Sales Expert

Mar 2006 – Sep 2007

Dena Sanat (www.denasanat.com)

- Explaining technical security solutions to customers, understanding their requirements and providing basic site surveys, system designs and quotations
- Making sure the financial targets are made
- Preparing the marketing strategies in different solutions (CCTV, Access Control and Fire Alarm)
- Annual planning of participating in related exhibitions (directly or in common with agents of other cities)
- Monthly reporting of the sales department and the feedback of activities

Sales Engineer

Jul 2005 – Aug 2006

O-one Technology Development (www.oone.ir)

- Designing security solution systems according to the site surveys and evaluation forms
- Following company policies in making business relations to market
- Participating in related exhibitions

Education

- MSc in Economics (Economic Systems Planning) [will be started in September 2021]
- Bachelor of Science (BS) in Small & Medium-sized Enterprises Management (SME Management)
- Associate of Science (AS) in Airframe Mechanics and Aircraft Maintenance Technology/Technician from Civil Aviation Technology College of Iran
- A&P (Airframe & Powerplant) License